[
  {
    "question": "A 22-year-old woman presents with daily band-like headaches over the past 2 weeks. Headaches more intense in back of head, precipitated by emotional stress. No focal neurologic or visual deficits.",
    "options": {
      "A": "Antidepressant drugs",
      "B": "Calcium-channel antagonists",
      "C": "Ergotamine-containing preparations",
      "D": "NSAIDs",
      "E": "Sumatriptan"
    },
    "answer": "D"
  },
  {
    "question": "A 40-year-old man complains of a severe headache of sudden onset that started 4 hours ago, likened to being kicked in the back of the head. He has vomited twice and is now feeling stiffness in his neck",
    "options": {
      "A": "Amaurosis fugax",
      "B": "Analgesic headache",
      "C": "Cluster headache",
      "K": "Subarachnoid hemorrhage",
      "L": "Subdural hematoma"
    },
    "answer": "K"
  },
  {
    "question": "A 35-year-old man has nocturnal attacks of severe periorbital headache for past 5 days. Each episode awakens him within 2 hours of falling asleep, lasts less than an hour, associated with ipsilateral rhinorrhea and lacrimation. Pupils equal and reactive, temperature 37°C, BP 125/75, pulse 72.",
    "options": {
      "A": "Acute glaucoma",
      "B": "Cluster headache",
      "C": "Migraine",
      "D": "Sinusitis",
      "E": "Tension headache"
    },
    "answer": "B"
  },
  {
    "question": "A 55-year-old woman with hypertension presents with 3 weeks of worsening headaches and language difficulty. She reports severe headaches waking her from sleep, worse in the morning, frequently associated with nausea. She complains of slowness of speech and difficulty with word-finding. Neurologic examination: slow, effortful speech with poor repetition, right pronator drift. MRI shows diffusely enhancing intra-axial abnormality in left frontal region. What is the most likely diagnosis?",
    "options": {
      "A": "Astrocytoma",
      "B": "Brain abscess",
      "C": "Cerebral infarct",
      "D": "Complicated migraine",
      "E": "Meningioma"
    },
    "answer": "A"
  },
  {
    "question": "A 25-year-old lady on contraceptive pills presented with headache, blurring of vision, and convulsions, She was afebrile. What is the most possible cause of her symptoms?",
    "options": {
      "a": "HSV encephalitis",
      "b": "Meningitis",
      "c": "Multiple sclerosis",
      "d": "Idiopathic intracranial hypertension",
      "e": "Brainstem infarct"
    },
    "answer": "d"
  },
  {
    "question": "An alcoholic patient presents with headache and confusion for 10 hours. What is the most likely diagnosis?",
    "options": {
      "A": "Acute subdural hemorrhage",
      "B": "Alcoholic ketoacidosis",
      "C": "Hypertensive crisis",
      "D": "Wernicke's encephalopathy"
    },
    "answer": "A"
  },
  {
    "question": "A 65 year-old woman with a history of unsteady gait of sudden onset associated with vomiting and headache for 12 hours, then she complained of an increasing drowsiness. What is your diagnosis?",
    "options": {
      "A": "Acute subdural hemorrhage",
      "B": "Cerebellar hemorrhage",
      "C": "Frontal subdural empyema",
      "D": "Herpes simplex encephalitis",
      "E": "Pituitary apoplexy"
    },
    "answer": "B"
  },
  {
    "question": "A 70-year-old woman presented with an acute, severe occipital headache, unsteadiness of her gait, and vomiting. She had a history of poorly controlled hypertension. On examination there was nystagmus to the left, ataxia of the left limbs, and gait ataxia. What is the most likely diagnosis?",
    "options": {
      "A": "Acute cerebellar hemorrhage",
      "B": "Basal ganglia hemorrhage",
      "C": "Pontine hemorrhage",
      "D": "Subarachnoid hemorrhage",
      "E": "Millard-Gubler syndrome"
    },
    "answer": "A"
  },
  {
    "question": "A 30-year-old female presented with a sudden onset of severe headache (the worst headache of her life), throbbing in nature and associated with neck pain and stiffness. What is the most likely diagnosis?",
    "options": {
      "A": "Migraine",
      "B": "Subarachnoid hemorrhage",
      "C": "Cluster headache",
      "D": "Temporal arteritis",
      "E": "Brain tumor"
    },
    "answer": "B"
  },
  {
    "question": "What investigations would you like to do for a 40yrs old woman with headache and blurring vision, overweight, acne, on oral contraceptive pill. CVS, Respiratory and GIT systems are normal.",
    "answer": [
      "CT brain, to exclude other pathologies.",
      "Lumbar Puncture with measurement of increased opening pressure."
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "A 19-year-old girl presents with headache, fever, photophobia and neck stiffness. Choose the most likely infecting organism from the options.",
    "options": {
      "A": "Campylobacter jejuni",
      "B": "Mycobacterium tuberculosis",
      "C": "Neisseria meningitidis",
      "D": "Pneumocystis jiroveci",
      "E": "Staphylococcus aureus"
    },
    "answer": "C"
  },
  {
    "question": "A 32-year-old female presents with headaches. Severe frontal and occipital headache present as soon as she wakes. She gave birth one month ago and has not felt well since. Exam reveals bilateral blurring of optic discs with pupil sparing and right 3rd nerve palsy. What is the most likely diagnosis?",
    "options": {
      "A": "Brainstem Cerebrovascular Stroke",
      "B": "Herpes simplex encephalitis",
      "C": "Meningococcal meningitis",
      "D": "Sagittal sinus thrombosis",
      "E": "Sphenoidal wing meningioma"
    },
    "answer": "D"
  },
  {
    "question": "A 52-year-old man with ischemic heart disease requires treatment for an acute migraine attack that has not responded to paracetamol.",
    "options": {
      "A": "Acetazolamide",
      "B": "Amitriptyline",
      "C": "High-dose aspirin and metoclopramide",
      "D": "Propranolol",
      "E": "Sumatriptan"
    },
    "answer": "C"
  },
  {
    "question": "A febrile patient with temp. 40°C, confused & irritable. His mouth is free. Chest is clear, no abnormality detected in CVS, Abdomen is soft, lax, no organomegaly. Lower & Upper limbs normal Apart from skin rash.\nWhat is the clinical diagnosis?",
    "answer": "Meningitis"
  },
  {
    "question": "What other 2 signs to look for in above patient?",
    "answer": ["Kernig’s sign", "Brudzinski's sign"]
  },
  {
    "question": "What is the differential diagnosis for the above patient?",
    "answer": ["Brain abscess", "Encephalitis", "Cerebral malaria"]
  },
  {
    "question": "How to confirm the diagnosis in above patient?",
    "answer": "Lumbar puncture for CSF analysis, Only if no signs of raised intracranial pressure (do CT first if necessary)"
  },
  {
    "question": "Outline the management of the above patient?",
    "answer": [
      "ABCs.",
      "IV fluids.",
      "Antibiotics: start empiric therapy with Ceftriaxone, then shift to benzylpenicilline when Neisseria meningitidis is confirmed."
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "An 82-year-old lady is admitted from her nursing home with headache, photophobia and neck stiffness. Temperature 39°C, pulse 115/min, no skin rash or focal neurological signs, GCS 15/15. CT shows no contraindication to lumbar puncture. CSF Gram stain shows Gram negative cocco-bacilli, culture confirms Haemophilus influenzae meningitis. What chemoprophylaxis should be offered to her contacts?",
    "options": {
      "A": "Azithromycin",
      "B": "Ceftriaxone",
      "C": "Ciprofloxacin",
      "D": "No chemoprophylaxis required",
      "E": "Rifampicin"
    },
    "answer": "E"
  },
  {
    "question": "A 17-year-old female presents with three attacks of headache over six months. Headaches severe, right-sided, lasting 12 hours, associated with nausea and photophobia. Each preceded by spots before her eyes. Most appropriate initial treatment?",
    "options": {
      "A": "Diclofenac at the onset of the next attack",
      "B": "Ergotamine suppository at the onset of the next attack",
      "C": "Paracetamol plus metoclopramide at the onset of the next attack",
      "D": "Prophylaxis with propranolol",
      "E": "Sumatriptan at the onset of the next attack"
    },
    "answer": "E"
  },
  {
    "question": "A 65-year-old woman presents with a headache lasting a few weeks. She gets pain in her mouth during meals and her scalp is tender on palpation. Recommend appropriate treatment.",
    "options": {
      "A": "Hydrocortisone",
      "B": "Morphine",
      "C": "Prednisolone",
      "D": "Propranolol",
      "E": "Sumatriptan"
    },
    "answer": "C"
  }
]